techtricksworld.com 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy - TechTricksWorld

**[TechTricksWorld](http://www.techtricksworld.com/)** is a tech blog which has the utmost respect for your privacy. While you are online on our website, we take up the responsibility to secure your privacy. Following is our blog’s Privacy Policy which will help you understand, what information do we intend to collect and how we make use of this information? We will also mention here, who has access to your personal information. For any further queries, **[feel free to contact us](http://www.techtricksworld.com/contact-us)**.

##  **We Collect Your Information**

We collect your personal information, when you access our website. Some of the ways in which we collect information are as follows:

  * ###  **Email Subscription**

In case if you subscribe to our website, you provide us with your email ID. On the other hand, if you contact us with some query via email, we make it a point to retain your email address, and your email along with our response to your email.

  * ###  **Giveaways**

Most of the giveaways have a form to be filled, where you have to submit your Name & Email ID along with some other details. These contact details are used to contact the winners of the giveaway.

  * ###  **Comments**

While commenting on any of the articles that were posted on the website, we ask you to provide some information about yourself. This information includes your name, your email address (which does not get published) and the website you are affiliated with. While providing your name and email address is mandatory, the option of providing the website link is completely optional.

  * ###  **Cookies**

For those of you who are not familiar with this term, a cookie is a part of file stored in the user (that is your) computer, along with some information about you. In order to track whether the users return, our website uses cookies. However, we do not have any control over the cookies and very limited information is collected with the help of cookies. ****

##  **How We Use Your Information**

###  **The Information That You Have Provided To Us**

The information that you have provided to us about yourself is basically used for effective administration of the website. When you email us your queries regarding the website or any other detail, we make it our top most priority to clarify your doubts. On the other hand, when you apply for subscribing, we send you emails of our post updates. You can also comment on any of our posts, in order to put across your opinion. This way we get a feedback from you and we use it for working more efficiently. When you provide your information to us, we basically use it to stay connected with you.

###  **The Information That We Collect From Cookies**

In order to distinguish you from other users, TechTricksWorld has made it a point to use cookies. Sometimes we also cookies so that we can give you easy access to our website. In some other cases, we make use of cookies in order to prevent you from viewing unnecessary advertisements on our website.

With the help of cookies we get a basic idea about how many people are accessing our website from across the world, thus identifying our website’s popularity. In doing so we get a genuine and honest feedback from our users, which encourages us to perform better each time. We use this information to give better service to our customers.

We generally do not save the personal information which we receive from the cookies. Besides the cookies doesn’t even allow us to access any of your personal information.

###  **Sharing Your Information**

We ensure that the information that we collect is collected to improvise the quality of service we provide to our users and to enhance the quality of the content that is posted on our website. The information that we collect about our users, remains with us and we do not share this information with any third party for any monetary benefits.

##  **Disclaimer**

[ **TechTricksWorld**](http://www.techtricksworld.com/) essentially focuses on helping its viewers acquire profound knowledge in the field of SEO, Social Media, Making Money Online, Blogging, Softwares, Gadgets etc… We try to make sure that the content (text, images, videos etc..) provided to the readers of the blog is authenticated and original. However, at times the content that is displayed on the blog may not be original and might have been reproduced from elsewhere, and also we do not affirm the correctness and the fairness of the source of the data.

While reviewing the software, games, gadgets or other products/services; we usually try to use the reviewed product / service. Nevertheless, at times, the reviewed product or service might not have been accessed by us.

Sometimes, even the hired content writers or other guest / ghost bloggers might furnish the data to publish on the blog, and this content might not have been verified by owners of TechTricksWorld.

Having said that, every effort has been made to keep the data on the blog original and authenticated, however, the owners also do not affirm the originality and authenticity of the content on the blog. All in all, we shall not be entertaining any claims for losses /  damages caused due to the content of our website.

We are Amazon and Flipkart affiliate so we do use the affiliate links and the product images from their site when we post review various products from their sites or make lists of products. 

All the disputes are subject to Mumbai jurisdiction only.
